VOLKAN AYGUN

Sengul Sok. Cagla Apt. No:3 Daire: 23 Bostanci, Kadıkoy, İstanbul Tel: +90 532 2559168 volkan.aygun@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

An energetic, motivated and highly dynamic sales manager with good strategic, sales and marketing skills and extensive experience and proven success in developing new business. Have strong analytical skills with the capability of assessing conditions and implementing appropriate intervention. Is a resourceful thinker who can discover solutions for complicated problem scenarios.

CAREER HISTORY

Lanxess 10.2019-Present

Sales Manager, BU Rhein Chemie, Turkey

- Develops local strategies for sales activities in accordance with BU's policies and strategies
- Steers local sales organization of 2 colleagues
- Executes go to market strategy for the product groups for Rubber and Tire industries
- Ensures frequent personal contact with major Tire and Rubber accounts
- Sets targets, monitors achievement and develops contingency plans for business segments
- Responsible for people development, e.g. evaluation, training, coaching, talent identification, promotion
- Implements performance management tools according to corporate guidelines

Clariant 05.2017-10.2019

LBL Masterbatch Sales Manager, Turkey

- Develops local strategies for sales activities in accordance with BU's policies and strategies
- Develops budgets for the country together with the Head of LBL Turkey
- Steers sales organization of 9 colleagues (Local Sales Team and CSD)
- Executes go to market strategy for the target sectors and product groups
- Ensures frequent personal contact with major customers
- Sets targets, monitors achievement and develops contingency plans for business segments
- Responsible for people development, e.g. evaluation, training, coaching, talent identification, promotion
- Implements performance management tools according to corporate guidelines
- Decides on sales force employment and deployment

Clariant Turkey A.S.

04.2013-05.2017

LBL Masterbatch Sales, Reg.KAM for L'Oreal

- Manages sales and customer service activities operationally in accordance with the sales and marketing guidelines.
- Develops account sales strategy for achievement of country sales objectives
- Monitors account receivables of accounts and manages over dues.
- Provides technical support and expertise to maintain and develop value based pricing

BASF Chemetall Istanbul, Turkey

03.2010-04.2013

Sales and Technical Services Specialist

- Sales and Technical support by regular visits for automotive and white goods industry.
- Develops customer relations by presenting good communication and sales skills.
- Maximize the satisfaction of customer's needs by identifying value engineering and cost reduction initiatives.
- Coordinating Chemetall Distributors with technical support and setting sales targets.

VOLKAN AYGUN

Sengul Sok. Cagla Apt. No:3 Daire: 23 Bostanci, Kadıkoy, İstanbul Tel: +90 532 2559168 volkan.aygun@gmail.com

Elastron 06.2009-02.2010

Senior Business Development

- Involvement in developing business for TPV seals in general industry customers.
- Maintain initial relations with customers in basis of line trials.
- · Key user role in implementation of CRM system.
- Technical support in the implementation of new products into customer lines.

Petrokem 10.2008-06.2009

Sales Engineer

- Responsible for the purchasing, sales and marketing activities of petro chemistry products.
- Observing the commodity plastics market for informing the top management for buying and selling decisions
- Maintaining relationships with new suppliers to be represented in the domestic market.

AKM Metalurji 10.2007–10.2008

Sales Engineer

- Responsible for the purchasing, sales and marketing activities of metallurgical products.
- Observing the commodity market for informing the top management for buying and selling decisions for Aluminum and non-ferrous segment.
- Maintaining relationships with new suppliers to be represented in the domestic market.

EDUCATION

GALATASARAY UNIVERSITY Engineering Faculty, Engineering Management	08.2005-08.2006
ISTANBUL TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY Chemistry-Metallurgy Faculty, Chemical Engineering	09.2001-05.2005
LULEBURGAZ ANATOLIAN HIGH SCHOOL	08.1994-06.2001

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth and Place: 16 February 1983, Kirklareli

VOLKAN AYGUN

Sengul Sok. Cagla Apt. No:3 Daire: 23 Bostanci, Kadıkoy, İstanbul Tel: +90 532 2559168 volkan.aygun@gmail.com

REFERENCES

Alessandro Dulli

Vice President Marketing at Polymateria

+ 39 335 709 1706

Ufuk Açıkel

Country Manager Turkey for Avient Corporation / former Clariant Masterbatches

+90 532 246 0360

Alessandro Cavassi

Head of Sub-Region MEA for Avient Corpotation / former Clariant Masterbatches

+39 335 632 6781

Gregor Kiel

Vice President, Global Head of BL Paints & Material Protection

+49 162 885 7095

Berhan Dayıoğlu

Finance Manager Global Strategic Projects at Sandoz

+49 151 111 62242